Rogvi David Arge

Data Science & Optimization Consultant

+45 5042 5002 argeinnovations@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/rogvidarge/en github.com/rogvid

SUMMARY

Data Scientist with more than 4 years of experience in agile project development and a passion for deep learning, predictive analytics and optimization. Vast experience in data wrangling, exploratory data analysis, machine learning and data visualization and applying these skills to generate corporate wide improvements.

KEY COMPENTENCIES

Python Machine Learning Data Science Deep Learning Data Visualization AWS

Problem Solving Critical Thinking Communication Data Analysis SQL TensorFlow

Keras NoSQL NLP Optimization API Flask CI CD Statistical Modeling Analytics

Git Docker Operations Research D3 JavaScript HTML CSS C# Azure SCRUM

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

 Spearheaded a paradigmshift of the transportation & logistics industry in two successful data science projects over a period of 5 months

Freelance Data Science Consultant | DFDS A/S

Dec. 2018 - May. 2019

- Spearheaded a paradigmshift of the transportation & logistics industry

 Peduced PMSE of prediction algorithm by 20% by helping to implement
 - Reduced RMSE of prediction algorithm by 20% by helping to implement a number of scalable machine learning models
 - Enabled a completely new transportation planning methodology by implementing dynamic optimization tool that visualized optimal plan in real time

Data Scientist | ATP

Feb. 2017 - Dec. 2018

Matured and overhauled the fraud detection efforts within social benefits using various data science approaches

- Reduced payments of social benefits to fraudulent people by more than 10 mio. using expert systems
- Enabled investigation of people with complex fraud patterns by implementing a hybrid machine learning-expert system model
- Decreased prediction failures caused by server downtime by building a Flask based ser- ver/database monitoring system

Data Analyst & Programmer | ConWX

Apr. 2015 - Feb. 2017

Used analytics and machine learning to increase client revenue and implemented software solutions to distribute these models to customers

 Greatly increased monthly revenue of one of our largest clients by improving our forecasts by 18%

- Enabled forecast evaluations by leading the design, development, and implementation of a forecast monitoring system learning-expert system model
- Decreased prediction failures caused by server downtime by building a Flask based ser- ver/database monitoring system

Student Assistant | Ramboll

Mar. 2011 - Apr. 2015

Developed excel macros in VBA for various departments

- Reduced walltime of building energy calculation by porting the existing excel solution to C++
- Enabled simulation of various energy dependent building parameters by creating an integration between excel and BE10

EDUCATION HISTORY

M.Sc. in Physics | University of Copenhagen

Aug. 2012 - May. 2015

Focused my studies on applied mathematics, computational physics, machine learning, statistics and mathematical modeling. Wrote my thesis "Inflammation of the Central Nervous System - Modeling Multiple Sclerosis as a Motile Excitable Medium" under Professor Mogens Høgh Jensen

B.Sc. in Physics | University of Copenhagen

Aug. 2009 - Jun. 2012

Focused my studies on quantum optics, solid stats physics, laser physics, optics, and experimental physics

CERTIFICATES

Applied Social Network Analysis | Coursera

Feb. 2018

Python based course on Social Network Analysis, developing essential knowledge in the field of SNA.

Deep Learning Specialization | Coursera

Sep. 2017 - Feb. 2018

Development of deep learning models in Tensorflow & Keras. Specialization taught by Andrew Ng on Coursera. Notable projects in Image Recognition, Deep Learning, Transfer Learning, Convolutional Neural Networks, Recurrent Neural Networks, Speech Detection, Speec Recognition, Generative Adversarial Networks, and Trigger Word Detection

Data Analyst Nanodegree | Udacity

Jul. 2015 - May 2017

Project based courses teaching essential knowledge and skills for data scientists. Notable projects:

- Copenhagen apartment price evolution. Map visualizing the evolution of apartment prices in greater copenhagen
- Investigating fraud in Enron financial data and email corpus.

LANGUAGES

Faroese, Danish English Swedish, Norwegian, French, German Native Language Professional Proficiency Elementary Proficiency